二零二零年全市初中毕业升学考试
英语试题。
咦，第一部分，听力，
开始试音。
Hi, Tom. I'm making some plans to work in an old people's home this summer.
Really? I did that last summer.
Oh, what did they ask you to help out with?
things like reading the newspaper to the old people or just talking to them.
They told me stories about the past and how things used to be.
That sounds interesting.
Yeah, a lot of old people are lonely.
We should listen to them and care for them.
You are right.
I mean, we are all going to be old one day, too.
是因到此结束，听力考试正式开始。
第一大题。
听力测试，共三节，满分二十五分。
第一节，共五小题，每小题一分，满分五分。
听下面五段小对话和对话后的问题。
从每小题
,B Question. What color is Peter's ruler?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
每段对话仅读一遍。
Two. Can I help you?
Yes, please. I need a sweater for school.
Question. Where are probably the two speakers?
Three. Have you seen Mary?
There is a letter for her.
She left with Kate just now.
You can give it to Jane.
Thanks. Who is the woman looking for?
Four. What's your favorite subject,
I like science.
What about you, Mary?
I like Chinese and music.
Chinese? I think it's difficult.
Question. Which subject does Bill like best?
Five. How old are you, Jack?
I'm twelve, Mrs.
Turner. You are three years younger than my son.
Question. How old is Mrs.
Turner's son? Two.
第二节，共十五小题，
每小题一分，满分十五分。
听下面三段长对话和一段独白，
每段长对话。
话或独白后，有几个小题。
从每小题
is Peter's ruler?
Two. to watch TV tonight, Sam?
三个选项中，选出最佳选项。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六。
小题。
Well, there's nothing interesting on.
My favorite program, Animal World, comes on at eight o Oh, I forgot that it was on
tonight. Let's watch it.
Are there any other interesting programs?
The paper says there will be a football match at two o tomorrow morning.
That's my favorite program.
But two o 'clock in the morning?
Forget it. It's too late.
Do you want to watch TV tonight,
Well, there's nothing interesting on.
My favorite program, Animal World, comes on at eight o Oh, I forgot that it was on
tonight. Let's watch it.
Are there any other interesting programs?
The paper says there will be a football match at two o tomorrow morning.
That's my favorite program.
But two o in the morning?
Forget it. It's too late.
听下面一段对话，回答第。
小题。
I'll go to London next week, so I'd like some information about your flights there.
Okay, well, there are flights on Monday, Wednesday, Friday and Saturday.
And what time do they leave?
At three p.m.
Okay, Monday is better for me.
I'm in Center Street.
How can I get to the airport?
Oh, you must get to the airport at one thirty, so you have to take the twelve o bus
from the bus station in Center Street.
And how much is the ticket to London?
Well, it's four hundred dollars.
But if you have a student card, you can pay only half of the price.
Yes, I've got a student card.
Here it is.
Okay. And here is the money.
Thanks. I'll go to London next week, so I'd like some information about your flights
there. Okay, well, there flights on Monday, Wednesday, Friday and Saturday.
And what time do they leave?
At three p.m.
Okay, Monday is better for me.
I'm in Center Street.
How can I get to the airport?
Oh, you must get to the airport at one thirty, so you have to take the twelve o bus
from the bus station in Center Street.
And how much is the ticket to London?
Well, it's four hundred dollars.
But if you have a student card, you can pay only half of the price.
Yes, I've got a student card.
Here it is.
Okay. And here is the money.
Thanks. David, you are a at a sleep laboratory?
听下面一段对话，回答第十二至十五小题。
Yes, I am.
Why do you study sleep?
Because sleep is important.
In some jobs, people work a lot of hours.
For example, police officers often work twelve hours.
They are tired at work, but they can't sleep.
We can help people, but we don't understand sleep well.
Okay. And how do you study sleep?
People come to our laboratory.
They sleep and we watch them.
Do you do experiments?
Yes, we do.
For example, we change the light.
We use different colors of light, blue light and red light.
And what are the results with the different colors?
Well, red light usually wakes people up.
So, is blue light good for a tired person at work?
Possibly. We aren't sure.
We don't understand how it works.
Okay, David. Thank you very much.
You're welcome. David, you are a at a sleep laboratory?
Yes, I am.
Why do you study sleep?
Because sleep is important.
In some jobs, people work a lot of hours.
For example, police officers often work twelve hours.
They are tired at work, but they can't sleep.
We can help people, but we don't understand sleep well.
Okay. And how do you study sleep?
People come to our laboratory.
They sleep and we watch them.
Do you do experiments?
Yes, we do.
For example, we change the light.
We use different colors of light, blue light and red light.
And what are the results with the different colors?
Well, red light usually wakes people up.
So, is blue light good for a tired person at work?
Possibly. We aren't sure.
We don't understand how it works.
Okay, David. Thank you very much.
You're welcome. A farmer who was very hardworking, but his three sons didn't like
听下面一段独白，回答第十六至二十小题。
farm work. When the farmer was dying, he called the three sons to him and said, My
sons, there is a box of money in our olive orchard.
Go for it if you want it.
The sons worried that someone else could take it away, so they asked the father to
tell them where the money was.
But he said nothing more.
After the farmer was dead, the sons went to work to find the box of Because they did
not know where the money was, they dug the soil everywhere around the orchard three
times. But they found nothing.
The three sons were disappointed to have all their work for nothing.
The next year, the olive trees grew nice and big fruit.
When the fruit was sold, the sons got a whole box of money.
And when they saw how much money had come from the orchard, they suddenly understood
what the father meant.
There was once a farmer who was very hardworking, but his three sons didn't like
farm work. When the farmer was dying, he called the three sons to him and said, My
sons, there is a box of money in our olive orchard.
Go for it if you want it.
The sons worried that someone else could take it away, so they asked the father to
tell them where the money was.
But he said nothing more.
After the farmer was dead, the sons went to work to find the box of money.
Because they did not know where the money was, they dug the soil everywhere around
the orchard three times.
But they found nothing.
The three sons were disappointed to have all their work for nothing.
The next year, the olive trees grew nice and big fruit.
When the fruit was sold, the sons got a whole box of money.
And when they saw how much money had come from the orchard, they suddenly understood
what the father meant.
In Being polite can make you popular.
第三节，共五小题，每小题一分，满分五分。
听短文，填写表格，每空一词，短文读两遍。
It is never too late to begin.
Here are a few tips.
First, be kind to people.
Give help to those who are in trouble.
Remember that by helping them, you are also making yourself happy.
Second, help strangers.
Helping someone who has difficulty climbing stairs is a good way to start.
Remember that someday you may need help and a stranger may come to help you.
Third, write or say something.
You can write thank you notes to people who help you.
Make cards for sick friends and say goodbye to people who are leaving.
Last, after attending a party, help the host clean up.
It may take you only a few minutes, but your help is quite important to a person who
is tired. Being polite can make you popular.
It is never too late to begin.
Here are a few tips.
First, be kind to people.
Give help to those who are in trouble.
Remember that by helping them, you are also making yourself happy.
Second, help strangers.
Helping someone who has difficulty climbing stairs is a good way to start.
Remember that someday you may need help and a stranger may come to help you.
Third, write or say something.
You can write thank you notes to people who help you.
Make cards for sick friends and say goodbye to people who are leaving.
Last, after attending a party, help the host clean up.
It may take you only a few minutes, but your help is quite important to a person who
is tired.
听力测试到此结束，请同学们接着做笔试部分。